Alright, so we're not yet to the point where we
can tell intentionally funny stories.
What can we do with language?
Well I mentioned Siri. Siri may not be
the best at telling bedtime stories
but Siri does some amazing things, and the
pieces that make that up are
actually used in many places in industry.
There's automatic speech recognition,
where you go from speech to text.
There's text-to-speech synthesis which
is an easier problem where you go from the text
to the speech. And then there's dialogue systems
that integrate all this together,
linguistic analysis.
Let me show you what a
speech recognition system looks like
just kind of when you point it at the TV.
So this is not customized to a
specific speaker, this is not over some
great microphone like how your phones
have really sophisticated microphones
these days.
This is just plugged straight into the TV as essentially
automatic transcription. Let's see
how well it does, and in particular watch the
errors.
So, what's interesting about this. First of all,
is it good? Is it bad?
It does a lot of stuff.
It does a lot of things right. It makes some
mistakes.
The mistakes are of multiple kinds, so for example, here
"The classmates said their final goodbyes".
That's like good buys like Best Buy.
right. That is exactly the sounds that
the reporter said.
The failing here in this case was not
in the acoustic modeling which tries to
connect
the wave forms to the underlying
linguistic sounds.
Here the failing is there multiple
things that sound the same.
You gotta figure which one the reporter
could possibly mean in the context.
This is a sad story right. Somebody died,
people are not going shopping, right, and
we know this is humans, but the
system does not and so in this case this
isn't a problem the language model. there
are other cases here where the problem is
more in the acoustics and putting all the stuff
together in some probabilistic framework
that lets you reconcile it all,
that's a big part of how speech
recognition works.
We'll have more discussion on that later.
We can do more with language than just
manipulate the signal from speech to text.
This is actually my research area. We
can do things like question answering.
We talked a little about Watson and
we'll have a lot more
later in the course about Watson.
So Watson is basically a question answering system.
Like, yeah, there's this layer of remembering
to phrase it as a question 'cause
you're on Jeopardy and making sure you
wager the right amount on the
Daily Double and that kinda stuff but to
a first approximation a question comes in,
Watson kind of has to
dig through a lot of information like
you know largely Wikipedia
and connect up some answer to the
question,
so that you know how to respond.
Basically a question answering system,
although an amazingly cool demonstration
of a very good one.
Another thing we can do is machine
translation. How many of you have used
a tool like Google translate?
So, you know, again, C-3PO. How good
is machine translation?
Well, depends on the language pair. I mean,
if I'm looking at a page, say in Chinese,
and I don't speak any Chinese, the machine
translation's pretty good because I was kind
of starting with nothing. But if I
actually speak the language maybe
I'm better off reading reading it in its natural form.
You can see some of these problems if
you do round trip from say, English to Chinese and back, and you can see how
good what comes back--actually that's a
good way to make an unintentionally funny story.
What else can we do: things like web
search, really are about a lot of things.
It has something to do with the
words but also kind of click stream information,
and kind of a local search and things
like that. And so there's a lot that goes into
web search. A big part of that is the
language.
Text classification, spam filtering.
Again, spam filtering is a case where it's
part language, part not language. We'll
talk more about spam filtering later
--and so on. These are the kinds of things
you can do in the domain of natural language.
We're no longer trying so hard
to tell stories funny or otherwise.
We're trying to build things like this.
And there has been a lot of traction.
There's a lot of stuff we can build.
We're not yet to C-3PO, but
we actually can now translate Russian,
which we couldn't do in the fifties even
though they thought would be able to do
it by the sixties. But now, today, we can.
It only took
something like twelve times longer than
they thought it would.